cybertext.wordpress.com 2019-06-28

# Privacy Policy | CyberText Newsletter

Your privacy is very important to me. As part of WordPress.com, certain personal identifiable information is collected and stored during your visit and as you interact with this blog.

## General

This blog is hosted by WordPress.com, which is owned by Automattic, and thus these Automattic policies apply:

  * General Data Protection Register legislation: <https://automattic.com/automattic-and-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/>
  * Privacy Notice for Visitors to Our Users’ Sites: <https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/>
  * Privacy Policy: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>.

Specifically, the Automattic Privacy Policy includes these statements:

> This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use:
> 
>   * Our websites (including automattic.com, wordpress.com, vip.wordpress.com, jetpack.com, woocommerce.com, polldaddy.com, gravatar.com, intensedebate.com, vaultpress.com, and akismet.com);
>   * Our mobile applications (including the WordPress mobile app for Android and iOS);
>   * Our other products and services that are available on or through our websites (including WordPress.com plans, WordPress.com VIP, Jetpack, the WooCommerce Services Extension, Gravatar, the IntenseDebate comment management system, and Akismet plans); and
>   * Other users’ websites that use our Services, while you are logged in to your account with us.
> 

## Data Collected and Used

Interacting with this blog by commenting or subscribing means that some personal identifiable data is automatically collected and stored during your visit.

### Commenting

WordPress.com uses Akismet spam control to minimise the spam received. This information is sent to Akismet for the sole purpose of spam checking: commenter’s name, email address, URL, IP address, and user agent (e.g. browser used, device’s operating system). Akismet minimises the need for repeated CAPTCHA processes for visitors to this blog who wish to comment.

The first time you comment on a post or page, I will be alerted that your comment is in the pending (or occasionally, the spam) folder. After reviewing your comment, I can choose to accept it or not. Once your first comment is accepted, you should be able to comment without needing further approval. As part of the comment process, you must submit your name (real or an alias), your email address, and, optionally, a web page address (URL). Also collected and stored automatically are the submission date/time you made the comment, and your IP address. If you decide to comment on any post or page while logged into and using a WordPress account, your user ID on that account as well as its URL (if available) will also be collected.

Your email address, which only I can see, will not be shown on the blog, and **I do not disclose that detail to anyone without your permission, except as required by law**. If I need to provide a complex or confidential answer to your comment, I may decide to reply directly to you in detail (via the email address you provided), and/or provide a brief or edited response on the blog. If you email me directly, all information in addition to your name, email address, and URL will be kept private and confidential and will only be used to directly respond to you via email. Any additional information you provide when contacting me will not be shared with any third parties and will be deleted after a reasonable period of time.

Your data will not be shared or sold to any third parties except in compliance with law authorities.

### Subscribing/Unsubscribing

You can choose to read my blog posts as and when it suits you (via a web browser), subscribe by email (you will receive an email for each new post), or follow using an RSS feed.

If you subscribe via email and later wish to unsubscribe from the blog, you can click the unsubscribe link displayed at the bottom of each email. You can ‘unfollow’ this blog via your RSS feed software. I have no way of unsubscribing or unfollowing you directly.

## Activity Tracking

### Cookies

This blog has cookies enabled by default by Automattic. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored on your computer/browser when visiting this blog. You can disable cookies in your web browser and do not have to consent to their use; however, this blog may require cookies to be enabled to function properly. When commenting on this blog, your name, email address, and URL (if provided when you submitted your comment) are stored in cookies. For more information on what cookies are and how to control cookie usage, see <https://automattic.com/cookies/>.

### Statistics

WordPress.com uses Jetpack for its general statistical analysis of readership; this information cannot be linked to specific individuals or accounts. Information collected about user activities on this blog includes user’s country (based on their IP address), links that are clicked, and any search terms used when accessing the blog via certain search engines or while viewing the blog. This information gives me general details of where blog users come from and which posts/pages are most viewed. I may share these general statistics in my annual blog summary. Further details on Jetpack’s privacy is here (<https://jetpack.com/support/privacy/>) .

## Other

### Advertising

I do not sell or provide any products through this blog and I pay a fee to WordPress.com to prevent advertisements showing on my blog. Therefore, to the best of my knowledge, your personal information is not used for commercial advantage.

### Changes to Policy

This privacy policy applies from the date below. Occasional changes may be made to this policy without warning. Check this page frequently to read any changes. By continuing to use this blog, you accept any subsequent changes made to this privacy policy.

Rhonda Bracey  
29 May 2018
